http://stjohnsharpenden.org.uk/information/privacy/

St Johns Church Harpenden
t 01582 712776
e St Johnâ€™s Parish Office
HomeAbout usOur newsletterWhoâ€™s whoParish centreChurch historyCalendarServicesBaptisms, weddings & funeralsChristmas servicesChurch lifeArts FestivalChildren & younger peopleInformationParish givingSafeguardingPrivacy
Home > Information
> Privacy
InformationParish givingSafeguardingPrivacy
Privacy
DATA PRIVACY NOTICE
The Parochial Church Council (PCC) of St John the Baptist, Harpenden
1. Your personal data – what is it?
Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data.  Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”).
2. Who are we?
The PCC of St John the Baptist, Harpenden is the data controller (contact details below).  This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.
3. How do we process your personal data?
The PCC of St John the Baptist, Harpenden complies with its obligations under the “GDPR” by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use your personal data for the following purposes: -
To enable us to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public in a particular geographical area as specified in our constitution;
To administer membership records;
To fundraise and promote the interests of the charity;
To manage our employees and volunteers;
To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications);
To inform you of news, events, activities and services running at St John’s.
4. What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
Explicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aid donations and keep you informed about diocesan events.
Processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement;
Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a religious aim provided: -
the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); and
there is no disclosure to a third party without consent.
5. Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church. We will only share your data with third parties outside of the parish with your consent.
6. How long do we keep your personal data[1]?
We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the guide “Keep or Bin: Care of Your Parish Records” which is available from the Church of England website [see footnote for link].
Specifically, we retain electoral roll data while it is still current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to 6 years after the calendar year to which they relate; and parish registers (baptisms, marriages, funerals) permanently.
7. Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: -
The right to request a copy of your personal data which the PCC of St John the Baptist, Harpenden holds about you;
The right to request that the PCC of St John the Baptist, Harpenden corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the PCC of St John the Baptist, Harpenden to retain such data;
The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time
The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;
The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office.
8. The Electoral Roll/ Stewardship Information
The Electoral Roll is compiled as a ‘legitimate interest’ of the church, and falls under statutory rules. It is therefore subject to those rules, rather than those of GDPR. However, the data collected is protected from being used for any other purpose.
Similarly, Stewardship Information is held to only fulfil that voluntary purpose and shared accordingly only with HMRC where Gift Aid has been opted for.
9. Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
10. Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the PCC Secretary -Jacky Dodd, or the Parish Office, at St. John the Baptist, Harpenden
You can contact the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.
In the event of a breach of data security, it will be reported to the Information Commissioner's Office, and advice will be acted upon.
Presented and passed at the PCC Meeting 19th March 2019
[1] Details about retention periods can currently be found in the Record Management Guides located on the Church of England website at: - https://www.churchofengland.org/about-us/structure/churchcommissioners/administration/librariesandarchives/recordsmanagementguides.aspx
Â  Â  Â  Safeguarding | St John's Church, St Johns Road, Harpenden AL5 1DJ | Privacy Notice
This church website is powered by Church Edit
